A Guide to the Zonta Club of Loudoun County Records, 1997-2007
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Zonta Club of Loudoun County Records 1997-2007
Thomas Balch Library
M 039
The Zonta Club of Loudoun records chronicle the organization's initial decade of local service, and include charters and by-laws, committee forms, membership rosters, newsletters, meeting minutes, service project report forms, and copies of The Zontian magazine.
Zonta Club of Loudoun County
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Brenda MacEoin, President, Zonta Club of Loudoun County, Leesburg, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2007.0082, 2009.0024
Historical Information
Zonta International, a global organization of women executives and professionals, was founded in 1919. With more than 31,000 members in 66 countries and geographic regions in 2010, Zonta advocates worldwide advancement of women through service initiatives. Its stated objectives also espouse promotion of "justice and universal respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms," as well as "work for the advancement of understanding, good will and peace through a world fellowship of executives in business and the professions."
The Loudoun Chapter of Zonta International, initially orchestrated by members of the Fairfax County branch, received its charter on 1 November 1997. Their projects have included assistance for the Transitional Housing Program of Volunteers of America, as well as joint efforts with Holiday Coalition, Interfaith Relief, Loudoun Community Free Clinic, and Brighten the Corner. Zonta remains active on both international and local levels.
Scope and Content
The Zonta Club of Loudoun records chronicle the organization's initial decade of local service, and include charters and by-laws, committee forms, membership rosters, newsletters, meeting minutes, service project report forms, and copies of The Zontian magazine.
The first box in the collection includes much of the club's primary documentation, such as its charter, membership directories, long-range planning, and activity descriptions of the Status of Women, Archives and History, and International Committees. Its folders span all active years of Zonta International's Loudoun branch. Box one also contains club agendas from 1997 through 2005, board meeting minutes from 1999-2006, and all service project report forms. These provide accounts of scholarship budgets, awards and recognition, planning workshops for promoting recruitment and publicity, as well as the cultural exchange between the Loudoun chapter and its sister club located in Burkina Faso, West Africa. The second box is comprised of program descriptions and handouts, press releases, newspaper articles, and event photographs from the years 1999-2007; it recounts the club's major campaign to raise awareness of human trafficking in the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area, as well as its extensive community service proposals. The third box of the collection consists of Zonta International's global objectives from the years 2001 through 2006, as well as biennium issues of The Zontian magazine dating from 1999 to 2006. Furthermore, it holds copies of all newsletters from the club's first ten years of existence. Newsletters from May 1997 to January 1999 were printed under the heading "Zonta Club of Loudoun County"; in February 1999, the current "Zircular" format was adopted for all subsequent newsletters.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Zonta Club of Loudoun County (M 039), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA
Zonta International, http://www.zonta.org/WhoWeAre.aspx.
Other Finding Aid
None
Technical Requirements
None
Contents List
- (Box 1)
  - By-Laws and Charters, 1997
  - Chartering Ceremony and Documentation, 1997
  - Basic Procedures for Membership
  - Officers and Committees, 1997-2007
  - Officers and Committees, 1999-2001
  - Officers and Committees, Highlights, Roster, 2005-2006
  - Organization, Membership and Classification Committee, 2003-2004
  - Organization, Membership and Classification Committee, 2004-2005
  - Status of Women, 2004-2005
  - United Nations, 2004-2005
  - Z Club, 2004-2005
  - ZISVAW, 2004-2005
  - Amelia Earhart Committee Form, 2004-2005
  - Archives and History Committee Form, 2004-2005
  - International Committee Form, 2004-2005
  - Public Relations Club Report Form, 2004-2005
  - ZISVAW Committee Project and Report, 2005-2006
  - Status of Women Committee, 2005-2006
  - Archives and Aviation Committees, 2005-2006
  - International Relations Committee, 2005-2006
  - Public Relations and Communications Committee, 2005-2006
  - Membership Rosters, 1997-1998
  - Membership Roster, 1999-2001
  - Membership Rosters, 2002-2004
  - Membership Rosters, 2004-2005
  - Membership Rosters, 2005-2006
  - Budget and Finances, 1997-2005
  - Fundraising, 1999-2001
  - Long-Range Planning and Public Relations
  - Agendas, Minutes, Committee Notes, Articles, 1997-1998
  - Agendas, Minutes, Committee Notes, Articles, 1999
  - Agendas, Minutes, Committee Notes, Articles, 2000
  - Agendas, Minutes, Committee Notes, Articles, 2001-2005
- (Box 2)
  - Committee Notes and International Service, 2003-2004
  - Board Meetings, 1999
  - Board Meetings, 2000
  - Board Meetings, 2001
  - Board Meetings, 2005-2006
  - Initial Service Projects and Reports, 1997-1999
  - President's Messages, 1999-2001
  - Service Mission, History, and Program, 1998-2000
  - District 3, Area 4 Events
  - Special Outside Events, 1999-2001
  - Planning Workshop, 2000-2001
  - Service Mission: Burkina-Loudoun Connector, 1999-2001
  - Zonta International: District 3 Service Committee Report Form, 2004-2005
  - Zonta Club of Loudoun County Service Projects, 2004-2005
  - Service Projects, 2005-2006
  - Letters, Press Releases, and Photographs, 1999-2001
  - Awards, 1998-2006
  - Newspaper Articles and Event Photographs, 2000-2001
  - Event Photographs: Holiday Coalition Dec., 2004
  - Miscellaneous Event Photographs, 2004-2005
  - Event Photographs and Brochures, 2004-2005
  - Miscellaneous Event Photographs, 2005-2006
  - Human Rights Conference: Photographs and Letters, 2005-2006
  - Loudoun Commission on Women Awards, 2005
  - Newspaper Articles, 2005-2006
  - Program Descriptions, 1999
  - Program Descriptions, 2000
  - Program Descriptions, 2001
- (Box 3)
  - Special Programs and Handouts, 2002
  - Special Programs and Handouts, 2005
  - Special Programs and Handouts, 2006
  - Special Programs and Handouts, 2007
  - Zonta International, 2001-2006
  - The Zontian Magazine, 1999-2001
  - The Zontian Magazine, 2002-2005
  - Zonta International: Biennium Highlights, 2004-2006
  - The Zontian Magazine, 2006-2007
  - Newsletters (Pre-"Zircular"), 1997-1998
  - Newsletters, 1999-2000
  - Newsletters, 2001
  - Newsletters, Jan. 2002-May 2003
  - Newsletters, June -Dec. 2003
  - Newsletters, Jan.-May 2004
  - Newsletters, June-Dec. 2004
  - Newsletters, Jan.-May 2005
  - Newsletters, July-Dec. 2005
  - Newsletters, 2006